good evening ladies and gentlemen a very
warm welcome to icici lombard general
insurance company limited
q4 and fy 22 earnings conference call
in the senior management we have with us
today mr bharara
executive director wholesale
please note that any statements comments
are made in today's call that may look
like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as future involved risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being expressed
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in the listen only mode and there
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes
should you need assistance during the
conference call please signal an
operator by pressing start and zero on
your touchstone phone
and now hand the conference autumn of
das gupta md and ceo icici lombard
general insurance limited thank you and
over to you sir
thank you
good evening to each one of you and
thank you for joining the earnings
conference call of ice and lumbar
general insurance company limited for q4
fi 22 and for the full year 202
i will give you a brief overview of the
industry trends and development that
we've witnessed in the last few months
post this our kfo which the gopal bala
chamberlain will share the financial
performance of the company for the
quarter and the year ended march 31
period
the industry registered a
gdpa growth of 11.1 for fi 22.
as for public disclosures the combined
ratio of the industry was 119.2
for nine months fi 22 as compared to
110.4 for nine months fi 21
and the industry reported a loss of 4.05
billion rupees as against profit after
tax of 55.6 billion rupees for nine
months fi 22. 21.
further the overall combined ratio for
the private multi-line general insurance
was 112
112 in nine months fy 22 as compared to
104.6 in nine months fi 201 2021.
the actually solvency at nine months fy
22 was worsened to 1.7 times as against
2.07 times at 9 months of fy 21.
so moving to the quarter under review
the industry delivered a mixed
performance
as for the data published by cm the new
vehicle sales witnessed step in close of
private car segment on the back of
supply chain supply side challenges
the two will assessment remained far
from recovery while the commercial
vehicle segment has shown growth
supported by underlying demand health
insurance on the other hand contributed
significantly to the overall industry
growth in line with the expectation and
is now the largest contributing segment
to the gdp of the industry
the commercial line witnessed robust
growth in sync with current market
environment
coming to the business impact for us the
community has grown it's grown in line
with the market growth of 12.7 percent
this is excluding crops and markets as
against the lower growth that we
witnessed till nine months of fi-22
within the quarter the growth momentum
has increased each month and the company
has significantly outgrown the market in
the month of march 2022.
coming to the growth for key segments
during the quarter for motors the
company has grown faster than the
industry and we have now attained market
leadership in this segment
for the year
our investment in the retail health side
has started
to show results and has resulted in our
agency channel premium growth of 29.5
for the quarter
as indicated in our previous calls after
1000 retail health agency managers to be
added to our employee base we have now
onboarded 750 of them during this fiscal
and the balance 250 offers have been
made
we expect the growth to accelerate in
the accident in the next few quarters as
the sales force starts getting
productive
the corporate agency channel including
vanquishers is back in the black with
overall growth of 19.4
within this ica bank distribution group
grew by 24.9
primarily driven by health indemnity sme
and motor business
and other distribution partners acquired
through the integration grew 15.9 during
the same period
our business source through our website
grew by twenty percent within this our
health business grew by twenty three
percent travel grew by hundred and
thirty percent and motor grew by ten
percent
business source through strategic
alliance partners in the digital
ecosystem grew by 98.2
overall our digital solutions has
enabled us to increase our digital
revenues by up to 7.74 billion for the
current year which accounts to accounts
to 4.3 of our overall gdp
as for the commercial lines are
concerned we experience robust growth
driven by 17.8 growth in the sme segment
let me now give you a update on some of
other key initiatives
on the integration i'm very happy to
share that as we speak isis lombard
stands as the second largest non-life
insurer in india
exactly as envisioned while evaluating
the scheme as a potential transaction
the integration enabled us to strengthen
our market leadership augment and
further strengthen our diverse
distribution channels
the revenue and operating operational
synergies the theory plans are on track
and gopal would talk about this in
detail
in his segment
our ielts care app has surpassed 1.3
million downloads with successful
submission of
over one lakh thirty thousand claims and
over seventy thousand tele consultation
requests
the recently added feature phase scan
helps users to keep a track of vitals
such as blood pressure hurt heart rate
respiration rate etc all without any
additional devices and from the comfort
and safety of one's home
i'll take care is built to be
user-friendly and a continuous
engagement platform which is increasing
our ability to cross-sell
we are also pleased to share with you
that we are the first large insurer to
move our entire core systems uh onto the
cloud this year
in our data center we had about 110
applications across 600 servers and
around 1 000 terabyte of data
moving our complete setup onto cloud has
given us some
immediate benefits including stability
availability and scalability
as such some of the investments that we
have made during the year in
distribution and technology is bearing
fruit and we expect to see momentum in
growth as we head into the next
financial year
we intend to continue with our expansion
across distribution digital technology
and clean services towards this we have
planned additional investments in the
range of rupees 1 billion to rupees 1.5
billion during this year during the
coming year i will now request gopal to
take you through the financial numbers
for the recently concluded quarter
thanks bhagav and good evening to each
one of you i will now give you a brief
overview of the financial performance of
the company for quarter 4 and fy 20 2022
we have put up the results presentation
on our website you can access it as we
walk you through the performance numbers
the effects of the re-merge and the
financials have been incorporated in the
form of opening network as on april 1
2021.
further the financials for the current
year represent numbers of the merged
entity and the comparative numbers for
the previous year in the financials
pertain to stand-alone isis and lombard
and hence not comparable
the company has enhanced disclosure
requirement of reserving triangles by
giving separate reserving triangles for
motor third party
and non-motor third party lines of
businesses
this is in accordance with the
regulatory guidelines on public
disclosures which is applicable to all
the players in the market
you may refer to slide number 29 and 30
of the investor presentation on the
reserving triangle disclosures
our gross direct premium income of the
company was at rupees 179.77 billion in
2022 as against rupees 140.03 billion in
fbi 2021. the industry reported a double
digit growth of 11.1 percent on a lower
base for a similar period
our gdpr growth was primarily driven by
growth in preferred segments given that
our approach has always been growing
business sustainably
the fire segment gdpi was rupees 27.5
billion in fy 222 as against rupees
21.58 billion in fbi 21.
as indicated in our results presentation
the overall gdp of our property and
casualty segment was rupees 50.24
billion in fbi 22 as against
39.29 billion in fbi 21.
on the retail side of business gdp of
the motor segment was at rs 82.8 billion
in fbi 22
as the game should be 70.2 billion in
fbi 2021.
to harness the potential of these
segments we have been expanding our
distribution network to increase
penetration entire free entire core
cities our agents which includes the
point of sale has increased to 88 539
as on march 31 2022 from 81 969 as on
december 31 2021.
the advanced premium numbers was rupees
33.68 billion
as at march 31 2022 as against
34.59 billion as at 31st december 2021.
resultantly combined ratio was 108.8
percent in fy 22
as against 99.8 percent in fbi 21 and
111 percent in nine months fbi 2022
combined ratio was hundred and three
point two percent in quarter four five
twenty two as against hundred and one
point eight percent in quarter four fy
twenty one
and hundred and four point five percent
in quarter three five twenty two
our investment assets rose to rupees
387.86 billion at mars 31 2022 from
rupees 374.54 billion at december 31
2021.
our investment leverage net of
borrowings was 4.23 times at mars 31
compared to 4.23 times at december 31
investment income was to be certain in
fy 22 as against rupees 21.96 billion in
fbi 21. on a quarterly basis investment
income was would be 7.06 billion in
quarter five twenty two as against
rupees five point three seven billion in
quarter four f by twenty one
our capital gains was at risk seven
point three eight billion in fy twenty
two as against rupees three point five
nine billion in fbi 2021
capital gains for quarter 4 fi 22 was at
rs 1.36 billion as against rupees point
six six billion in quarter four five
twenty one
the successful integration of the team
was business of barcelona to the company
has led to optimization of our
organizational structure
rationalization of offices
efficiencies in claim settlement
practices and technology applications
this will result in an annualized
synergy benefits of rupees 2 billion
of which rupees 0.7 billion has been
realized in f5 2022.
our profit before tax was rupees 16.84
billion in fbi 22 as against rupees
19.54 billion in f521
whereas pbt was rupees four point one
billion in quarter four five twenty two
as again should pays four point five
billion in quarter four f by twenty one
as explained above the company has seen
higher growth momentum in q4
fy22 and within that in the month of
march 2022
due to the current accounting norms this
results in uprinting of sourcing costs
whereas the benefit of earned premium
will be realized over the policy period
consequently profit after tax was rupees
12.71 billion in fbi 22 has against
rupees 14.73 billion in fbi 21
whereas profit after attack stood out to
be three point one three billion in
queue four five twenty two as against
rupees three point four six billion and
q four f by twenty one
the board of directors of the company
has proposed a final dividend of rupees
5 per share for fi
2022. the payment is however subject to
approval of shareholders in the ensuing
annual general meeting of the company
the overall dividend for fi 22 including
the proposed final dividend is rupees
nine per share
written on average equity was fourteen
point seven percent in fy twenty two as
against twenty one point seven percent
in five twenty one the return on equity
for q4 fi twenty two was fourteen
percent as against eighteen point eight
percent in q4 f521
solvency ratio was at 2.46 times at mars
31 2022
as against 2.45 times at december 31
2021 which continued to be higher than
the minimum regulatory requirement of
1.5 times as i conclude i would like to
reiterate that we continue to stay
focused on profitable growth
sustainable value creation and
safeguarding interest interest of
policyholders at all times i would like
to thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we will be happy to
take any specific questions that you may
have thank you
thank you very much we will now begin
the question and answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star in one on data stream
telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue you may press star and do
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question q assembles
participants
you may press star in one to answer
question
the first question is from the line of
srivas
shivani from clsa please go ahead
all right thank you for the opportunity
so a couple of questions i had i'll uh
probably just take two and then get back
in the queue uh first one is on the tp
hike rate uh that was announced and uh
what is the in what is your feedback on
how comfortable are you with the kind of
hike
uh that the regulator has proposed and
if you can help us get to an idea uh i
mean in spite of the hike i think given
that the car underlying car sales is
still weak if you can help us understand
how much the portion of your motor tp
book is private cars that would be the
first question second is on your uh
so just looking at your march 22 uh data
month the monthly data so the uh uh the
uh
the trend in your moto tp book was quite
strong and it was uh stronger than the
industry for that matter so if you can
give me uh so if you can help us
understand that and lastly on the loss
ratios for fire it's calmed down quite
dramatically in this quarter so if you
can help us understand that
thanks
so let me uh
take the questions
give the answer the same sequence so if
you look at the
pp rate hike
it's different across different segments
but the long term pp rates hike is
is a bit higher overall at a portfolio
level for the industry if weighted
average increase comes to roughly about
3 odd percent plus minus
you know honestly speaking given the
general inflation that we see
we would have
liked to see slightly higher rates in
certain categories in certain certain
categories we are fine with the rate
height that has been given
so in aggregate maybe a little bit
higher would have been appropriate is
our view on this
when is it expected as of now the
understanding is that it will come
around me
uh so that's where we are on the tp
hike
uh in terms of the mix i'll ask gopal to
answer the next point on the on the
private sector
yeah so uh sure as you can see uh so far
as we we have given on this slide uh
this split of od and tp which is roughly
about 40.68 billion is zone damage and
about
42.12 billion is third party
within that 42.12 private car first
party will be about 13.49 billion
coming back to your question on on
growth i think what's uh happened as
we've been kind of uh
explaining for the last few quarters is
that we took some calibrate call on uh
kind of
re-adjusting our portfolios away from
certain private car segments given the
pricing competition that we saw on the
private car and the owner website
and increasing uh
on the cv side again very calibrated
very selective calls
based on uh you know ground level
insights plus some experimentation that
we've been doing for the last three
years to
to figure out if uh some of those books
are going to be uh you know better
now when in retail when you cut down you
cut you know the the the number goes
away immediately but to build up it
takes some some time so actually on the
commercial side the growth momentum has
now picked up and what we've been kind
of uh indicating is that if you look at
our own portfolio mix unlike the market
where
out of the total motor book roughly 45
would be commercial vehicle for us that
was in the you know 15 to 17
that as we've been saying that should go
to roughly in the mid-20s
uh so that journey has now started uh we
will have to see if we can maintain the
momentum of growth of march but uh
clearly the the increase in the market
share of cv is something that we expect
going ahead
and your last question on fire loss
ratios share again i think i think
that's one segment where we keep talking
about saying that
a quarterly loss ratio may not
necessarily be reflective of the
underlying
outcome of the performance the better
number to look at will be more i would
say
financial year numbers in fact within
that
i mean there could be years where
because of let's say various large
losses or catastrophic years in fact
the loss ratio of that particular this
segment could get impacted
so hence
quarterly numbers may not necessarily
kind of reflect as i said the underlying
outcome look at more the annual numbers
for the fire part of the business
okay thank you
thank you
the next question is from the line of
abhishek saraf from jefferies
yeah thanks for the opportunity so i
just had a few following questions from
the earlier question asked so so you
mentioned that in the cv we are looking
at a higher
mix in the
so what is giving us confidence in terms
of meaning or containing the loss ratios
in that if you can just give us few more
details in the kind of experiments that
you have run and uh
where are we deriving this confidence
from uh secondly if you can help me
understand i believe that we have taken
uh hikes in motor od segment so what
would be the
average quantum of hike that we would
have taken and which kind of car segment
and
uh is it across the board that we have
taken in the new uh or basically in the
sense that for new cars or is it uh
accountable for new and old cars i have
a few more questions after this we'll uh
just after if you can answer this and
follow up here yeah
thank you so in
uh i think we've been talking about what
we've uh the way we've handled this
again if you again reiterate the point
it is not as if we believe the whole tv
portfolio is
hardly turned uh viable or sustainable
or profitable
if you look at the overall industry mix
cv will be as i said between 45 to 50
we are not talking about going anywhere
we are near that number now what we've
been doing for the last three years
again at various times we've talked
about this
is that based on ground level insights
uh based on some changes that we are
seeing both at
in certain micro segments certain
markets
uh based on certain usage patterns or
accident patterns that are changing in
certain states or
even some amount of
you know the the regulatory you know and
the compliance standards in some of
these markets
we
have been identifying some segments that
we believe are viable today than what
with what they were in the in the past
and what we've been doing as a company
is that we've been taking small bits to
see you know writing small amounts of
business
uh reserving at a level where we believe
uh you know it is very very conservative
but allowing the team to provide some of
those businesses to see what is the uh
experience that we have over the next
two to three years
some of those experiments have proved to
be in line with our expectations where
we are scaling up businesses
uh so so that's the confidence that we
are getting in terms of the uh the
segments of business now in terms of
and the approach that we are taking is
not just a loss issue
you're not looking at loss ratio you
look at the combined ratio in terms of
sourcing cost and loss ratio together
and wherever there is more uh viability
that's where we are taking those calls
uh in terms of uh
you know
in terms of uh private car the increases
reasonably across the board there are
one or two aims which haven't agreed
we are discussing but most of the areas
we've taken price increases
thanks for that answer
just if you can help us understand
you can share the
the quantum of hikes on an average that
we would have taken
it could be single regulation it's not
as if you've taken a huge hike it will
be a single digit right
okay okay that's very helpful uh
secondly uh on
just notice that in the calamity losses
uh
our share of losses have actually gone
up in this year
so
is it only because of integration with
bharti extra or is there more to it so
if you can help me understand
is our share of premium also have gone
up proportionately
in line with the losses as well
yeah so this was largely the cycle on
top that you're talking about if you
look at
[Music]
if you look at the last 10 12 cats our
share of losses being significantly
lower than our normal market share
in talk day we had two of our corporate
exposures that got hit so it was kind of
a you know unfortunate concentrated
event not
uh as if there was a large impact across
board so that's why we have a impact in
the docket because you know in those
cases you're in the western market where
we have a slightly higher share than our
natural market share so when you look at
a you know let's say lost share that
we've got relative to the market here in
these markets they get lower
yeah thanks virgo that's very helpful
thanks a lot
thank you
the next question is from the line of
madhukar ladda from illara capital
please go ahead
um
you know your od loss ratios for uh odi
and tp and especially tp actually
for
q4 have risen quite materially and
if you look at
the
quarter by quarter trend there is quite
a bit of volatility
now
uh you know when we look into the future
uh how should we be thinking about it
should we be thinking more in terms of
you know exit rate will be uh more
appropriate for next year
or the
the the fourier rate as a base
and so what what sort of
how how do you sort of project these
things or how do you look at it
so if you look at on the water own
damage segment
i think to my mind uh when you look at
more the exit rates for if quarter four
is will be largely reflective of the
trend line that one one could
potentially see so far as the way
forward is concerned and the reason why
we are saying is
in line with what we are discussed even
in our
earlier cause the thought process is to
try and see how we can get significantly
into
writing businesses which will be
relatively
driven in so far as more on uh let's say
high loss ratios and relatively lower
cost of sourcing late businesses
that's the thought process that we have
in terms of increasingly uh building the
book and that's the reason why i would
say quarter four on the motor own damage
is largely reflective of what one could
experience at least in so far as
the trend line for the future is
concerned having said that obviously we
continue to kind of micro segment the
portfolio to see which are the
segments which we want to select and
underwrite in terms of building the
overall book but the thought process is
in line with as i said
build a book which is relatively uh high
lr and low expense in so far as cost of
sourcing is concerned
on the third party portfolio i think uh
maybe i think what you could
the fuller numbers are largely
representative of what one could
experience in so far as
the way forward is concerned what are
force specifically i think
in line with what we had
done in quarter four of last year if you
recollect i think there were those
supreme court judgments which had come
through
this is which we had to kind of revisit
all the uh
outstanding cases that we had as of the
previous year and we had to kind of
strengthen the reserving requirements
assuming the fact that we could expect
an increase in average claim payout
consequent to those judgments on the
outstanding cases as well
on the similar lines i think what we
have experienced over the last couple of
years which is for understandable
reasons that uh
the courts in india which is
predominantly where you get bulk of the
motor third party orders being received
that has not been functioning at full
force while we have started to see
particularly maybe quarter four we have
already seen things coming back but at
least over the last i would say
three to six quarters the courts have
not necessarily been functioning at full
swing
what this does is obviously it kind of
starts to have an impact in so far as a
trend line of uh
settlements or cl or closures of cases
of third party that we would have done
related to the historical past
which would mean obviously given the
fact that there has been some lag in so
far as the extent of closures that we
would have normally seen which could
happen in the future period we obviously
have to kind of factor in for or maybe
build in an element of
further inflation assumption as a part
of our reserving book
particularly the element of interest
that we will have to add in so far as
our reserve reserving circumstance and
hence
uh the trend line for q4 on the third
party book will be more representative
of what one could expect so far as
future
trend line it comes
uh
that's what i'm doing
for even for tp
yeah and the other i think one should
also be mindful
is i think given the fact that we also
strengthened
the reserving
book of uh
the motor third party pool as you would
have seen in terms of the enhanced
disclosures
this element of increased
interest which will or inflation that
will build in as a part of the reserve
has obviously led in so far as the
earthquake motor pool book is concerned
we have obviously strengthened the
reserve however on aggregate basis
we have motor third party which is
actually reflecting a small amount of
reserve releases
when we are selecting business
and the attempt is to bring the combined
uh more under control
not just look at the loss issue
right
i'm guessing the comparative intensity
is driving us
in this direction
and and that's why we see you know
slightly probably lower commission
ratios and uh and expense ratios and
focus would that be right to say and
what would be like the trend for uh fi
so more than the company of computer
intensity is overall driving up the
overall combined for motor but if you
look at from a pure rv perspective
businesses which are high lr but low
expense tissue are better businesses
because the expense is upfront
a lot comes over the period
right right
and our expectation on how uh you know
like the integration with bharti and
what should be
uh our expense ratios and you know what
sort of expense ratios should we expect
in the effort to install like any
guidance on that
so into a synergy number gopal has
explained so very difficult to put out a
number uh
because i think on the one side as we
have put out what is what will be the
annualized energy numbers which we put
out as a part of the opening remark
which is rough
exactly
having said that i think what we will
continue to do when we look at let's say
23 or maybe the year thereafter we would
want to continue to kind of stay
invested
in building some of our expansion plans
particularly what we have spoken about
on let's say on the health
agency distribution side we want to
continue to stay invested on building
our digital opportunities that we see
including the investments in technology
and claim service so to some extent i
think lastly what we would end up is
obviously we would we are pretty much on
track in order to kind of realize the
benefits of synergy but at the same time
you would want to kind of use some of
these to kind of
increase
the opportunity that we see on account
of the renewed growth momentum that we
have seen for ourselves
so if you if you remember what we had
discussed when we did the
transaction we have said that for a
couple of years our combined issue will
be elevated and then it will start
coming down
if you see our combined ratio for this
quarter it's
related to the last two corners it's
already trending down
so that is an ongoing effort that we
will make to keep the combined ratio uh
under control now we also said that uh
as a strategy rather than bringing
combined down to 100 and delivering a 20
rv we want to keep on investing and
grow the book a bit faster
and final question uh i was reading the
notes to accounts uh there is a 65 crore
payment
of gst uh
under protest and an additional
agreement to pay 40 crores
can you explain that
and you know what is this the result of
uh
yeah the implication which i need
yeah so these are a couple of matters as
what we have put out uh as a part of
that disclosure on the notes to accounts
um
as an insurance company we are entitled
to claim
input credit
in so far as settlement of
motor claims related expenses are
concerned
both with respect to the arrangement
that we have either on a cash list or
whether on a reimbursement basis
in so far as the
gst department is concerned i think they
seem to kind of
allege that possibly we are not entitled
to claim certain inputs with respect to
some of those
motor claim related
expenses so that's one
the second is uh aspect is again with
respect to realization of as a part of
claim settlement again in the context of
motor portfolio we do kind of uh
end up
having certain element of
salvages
the view of the department is that on
that particular amount of salvage
amount that we end up realizing there
should be an element of gst
applicability on on the extent of
realizations that we have made we have
consulted
the
expert opinions as well as senior
councils on this in terms of the stand
that the company has taken both with
respect to the eligibility of input
credit or motor claim
as well as whether there will be any
element of applicability of gst so far
as salvage related
uh realizations are concerned the
standard of the company is pretty much
uh
well found and we and it is legally
correct
so at this point of time obviously
that's the reason why the amount that of
65 crores is paid under protest and
another 40 crores is something that we
will uh we are committed to pay
at appropriate point of time in due
course we will be filing a refund for
getting this amounts back but at this
point of time these amounts are largely
kind of paid under protest
what we clearly understand is obviously
this is something which is applicable
more at an industry level and hence to
that extent collectively we will the
strand of the industry is something that
we will work with and ensure that
we are able to get the right full amount
that is due back to us
understood understood so this is an
industry phenomena for the tax
department absolutely this is not
specific to isis and lombard this both
the issues are at an industry level
applicable to or
almost all the players in the world
got it
thanks thanks that's very helpful
thank you very much a request to all the
participants please restrict to two
questions for participants if time
common please come back in the question
queue for a follow-up question
the next question is from the line of
players chain from motilal roswell
financial service please go ahead
good evening everyone uh firstly uh
could you talk about or the health claim
ratios
on the retail side in particular and
also the group health uh how have they
played in q4 and uh
are they back to pre coverage levels or
there are certain elements which are
still there with respect to kovid and
how do you
see this going ahead i'll ask my second
question after that
so if you look at the split of uh
the health clock ratios which has been
given in the aggregate on the
presentation deck the breakup of that in
terms of
the employer employee portfolio or let's
say the corporate book that number for
quartet 3 was 93.1 percent that number
for quarter 4 is
95.3
and on the retail indemnity book
the losses ratios in quarter three was
about 65.7 and for quarter four that
number stands at about fifty seven point
six percent
yes uh so my question was uh you know
but it has and the repair definitely has
come off and so this is more of a
normalized level now and you can presume
it to be in a similar trajectory going
on right
so when you look at for example on the
corporate uh or let's say employer
employee book we have always spoken
about saying that
typically particularly the large
corporates tends to kind of operate at a
loss ratio which could be ranging
anywhere between 95 to 100 anywhere
between that
and in so far as the relatively small
and mid corporate book is concerned they
generally tend to kind of operate on
again the employer employee part at
anywhere between 90 to 95 which is why
on a blended basis
i think one generally gets to see the
loss ratios which are relatively around
those 95 threshold however the cost of
acquisition with respect to these
businesses particularly the large
corporate tends to be more direct and
hence to that extent on an aggregate
basis on a combined ratio book it
becomes viable for us to
underwrite having said that i think over
the last three or three quarters we have
been kind of talking through
particularly on the employer employee
book given the fact that we have seen
particularly this year the impact of
covet losses playing out
we have been affecting
clearly price increases
in so far as the renewal of the
portfolio is concerned while we had
indicated a price increase in the range
of 15 to 20 during our
quarter one earnings call but
subsequently as in when the actual
renewals have happened we have been able
to cite realizations which have been
slightly higher than that
and
even with the increased price
realization we have been able to clearly
hold on to in fact more than 90 percent
of the renewals in so far as
the employer employee or let's say the
corporate book is concerned
on the retail side again the thought
process is pretty much similar we
continue to keep looking at
the portfolio outcome in terms of what
is the desired loss ratio of the book
in general i think particularly the
indemnity book i mean depending on the
kind of book that you write the loss
ratios could range anywhere between i
would say 60 to 70 percent uh on a
steady state whereas the relative cost
of acquisition in the initial periods
would tend to be relatively higher given
the investment that we are making on
building distribution
so so that's that's what i would say in
so far as steady state loss experiences
are concerned both on the corporate
health or let's say the retail indemnity
book
okay
so the second question is more broad
level and a slightly longer term as well
so if you look at you know the efforts
that uh you know uh players like you all
have taken with regards to
uh
tech enabled cleaning settlement
processes on the health side or on the
motor side there's been several
initiatives that have been taken so do
you see that this
benefit the benefits of these efforts
will get more reflected in the pricing
coming down
or it would translate into more
combined ratio improvement uh so what
was the strategy that is adopting in
order to you know uh to take benefits of
these measures
so in terms of our long-term thought
process
this is just what you're talking about
is definitely correct but it's only one
element of what we are
uh how we are building this
so if you look at uh for example on our
claim um you know on the health side we
have launched that ai driven uh
authorization uh you know the ml engine
for settling uh
settling claims for uh corporates that's
currently running at
shade lower than sixty percent we
believe that number will keep increasing
as we go along but the approach is
across multiple levels so
uh if you if you think about it uh you
know the entire approach with i'll take
care was to look at uh an engagement and
con
you know a continuum of care approached
with corporates and we believe there are
multiple advantages of that beyond cost
sale upsell engagement etc
even at the time of claims we believe in
the longer term we will see some
benefits so we are already beginning to
see that uh all you know more than 40
percent of our corporate client claims
are coming even reimbursement cases are
coming through that app
uh we are
what we've seen in the past is when we
had moved the entire claim service
in-house back in
nine
because we run the complete data and do
a lot of analytics around it we are able
to control uh we could at that point in
the control flows better on top of it we
built a lot of capability again using
artificial artificial intelligence to
identify fraudulent claims better now as
we digitize the entire journey uh you
know the ability to run those engines
better becomes even
you know you know you have a ability to
run those engines even better so we are
already beginning to see the effects in
terms of claims being managed better
lastly i believe if we can drive the
video consultation tele consultation uh
you know as a model to even control
unnecessary hospitalization that could
be additional benefit so
overall there is a you know a very
comprehensive thought process in terms
of using technology to
both give better convenience and service
to customers and in the process improve
our relative
you know
loss costs for uh for the health claims
thanks thanks that's
thank you
the next question is from the line of
sanket gora
from spark capital advisors please go
ahead
okay thank you for the opportunity
with the price which we have taken in
motor od which we have said is largely
limited to the new business or we have
taken
the renewable premium too and then this
just wanted to check whether it is
limited to cars or even a new private
car or something
okay new private car so so there that
means
price like we have taken it does this
will will really help in improving the
loss ratios which which are currently
6822 and then 73 in four quarters so
expected improvement in the last ratio
because of this current price right
uh we will have to see a few things you
know one of the things that we are
watching very closely is the uh claim
inflation because the input costs are
going up for everyone so there is a risk
that there would be a claim inclusion
though till now in spite of the
inflation the team has managed it really
well
uh in terms of controlling the
acs you know average claim size
inflation
we are also you know driving a lot of
our
non oem source policies through our vpn
network that number has really gone up
this year so you know so we are trying
multiple strategies to prevent that from
going up but fact of the matter is that
we've seen significant increase in input
cost so there is a risk that there would
be an inflation because of that
if that happens then we may not be able
to see that you know benefit
but uh our sense is that at this point
in time where the private car only lost
issues are it needs a price increase if
so faster whether whether we factor in
the inflation or not so
uh so difficult to predict whether we
see improvement in loss ratio if the acs
implication doesn't happen the answer is
yes but we would have to guard against
that
but is this a industry phenomena that
files that you are seeing across the
page to happen or
the reason i am asking is that is the
potential risk for our market share loss
if you are the only guys who have taken
price there
uh we don't think so because uh you know
if you see
the market share the recalibration that
we have to do we've effectively done
this year this is your only market share
this year has gone down largely for that
reason right because we said that the
pricing was not uh adequate
uh where we are focusing on the effort
that we are building in terms of our
digital and agency channel uh you know
maybe some of the
you know the uh
you know the slightly older segment we
remain reasonably confident about
holding onto a market share in uh
ode site and something that we've been
saying that you know these two years
have been unusual because
you know people have benefited from
lockdowns and different times on the
motor portfolio right yeah and
traditionally whenever we see pricing
for 12 18 months and then things
you know correct back
we were talking about a pricing
correction
requirement even before the pandemic
right
so market was inadequate and ready for
that and then because of pandemic there
was people felt no need because of
frequency loss you know came down we
believe the market will have to
rebalance and correct this year and we
are seeing the stress
we are
seeing that even with price increase
price uh connection that we are doing we
are holding on to a market share you've
seen our march numbers
uh and the trend line event remains that
way
got it got it and and based on the tp
business uh you said that the meetings
also contribution also cv to the entire
tp business want to even reach to mid 25
and may 20th
so so this is wondering that have you
identified a particular product segment
where you can increase the test market
or contribution to 10 percentage whether
whether uh is it like spvs or auto
rickshaws or caliphate which which is
each of the segments which you have
identified which will drive this
uh increase in the contribution and and
so the loss ratio
yeah so it's not at that it's not just
that that level of segmentation is
significantly more granular
which obviously i don't want to get into
but we've looked at down to rto level
you know parameters take those calls not
just in terms of priority obviously at
no overarching level uh but we've done a
lot more deep analysis on the ground
in terms of
various factors we have beyond
categories and on that basis we've taken
this call if you see our market share
it's not a 10 shift that we're talking
about as we speak in the q3 number has
already come to close to 20
so we are talking about that number
going to mid teens mid-20s is
you know is not that big a
bigger stretch and as i said you know
when we started doing those experiments
about uh three years back
uh and we've watched the data for the
last three years almost 80-85 of the
experiments have worked out well for us
that's where can we are kind of uh
expanding
so yes a lot more micro segmentation
than those just a type of vehicle that
you're talking about
thank you
sorry to interrupt you so i requested to
come back in the question queue a
request to all the participants please
restrict to two questions per
participant if time permit please come
back in the question queue for a
follow-up question
the next question is from the line of
anira chitoshneewan from ubs securities
please go ahead
yeah i uh so wanted to understand uh
[Music]
level for us
but your voice is not coming very clear
may i request
is it better
yes yeah
and uh how much would that be changing
mixed within the motorcycle with higher
tvs would that material will be
different or with the pockets identified
i mean uh we have grown substantially
higher in the uh march uh
uh people wanted to make more sense how
much sustainability and uh
what kind of run rate we can expect
going forward
with the i can with the uh increasing
losses so that would be kind of you know
multiplying each other might be but uh
but what incremental healing can get
through
you know we're not sure about your
question it is still not clear but if
you are asking because of the pp price
hike and the run rate of growth that we
see in march
if it's linked so if you look at the
increases that is being proposed we have
to wait for the final
increases the increases for the
long-term tv policy is is a bit higher
so there our new business should benefit
uh the approach on the
cv business is what we explained earlier
that
we are picking up segments on our
combined ratio basis maybe the expense
ratio is a bit low but the loss ratio
could be a bit high but in aggregate our
combined issue is what we are focusing
on in terms of building in a more
disciplined manner
intensity doesn't go down
so how are we thinking about any other
strategy in mind
so as i said we think it should because
as i was explaining normally we've seen
over the last you know since
deterioration we've seen
these uh episodic uh you know aggression
in the in the private car in od segments
it does not happen beyond you know 18
months 24 months this time it's been
close to you know three and a half years
so two of those years have been pandemic
so we believe it was also given driven
by the fact that during pandemic people
saved uh on claims cost uh so if you
look at the the industry we don't
believe people can sustain these kind of
pricing aggression for too long
um but we love to see and as i said you
know when we are taking price increases
we are sensing that the market is also
uh you know expecting something like
this
okay and on the last question
with the agents on boarding
how much delta we can expect in terms of
growth coming in and what timeline if at
all
see you've seen a delta in the month of
march itself
we remain reasonably confident of
sustaining that going ahead in fact as
we explained that you know when you hire
agency managers they come on board which
takes about two to three months for them
to even build their channels of agents
and then they even start getting
productive so as of now we've only had
about 750 the balance 250 you know are
expected to come in
and the initial signs in terms of the
hiring of agents that they've done if
you look at this month at this quarter
uh you know we've had all added almost 8
000 agents
for this quarter so it's it's picking up
the traction is
high so there's no reason to think that
this uh gap in outperformance
reservation industry should
uh should drop off in fact we should be
able to build momentum we are actually
very optimistic about that that channel
that we are building if you see just the
last quarter our agency channel has
grown by about 29.5
so i don't see a reason why it should be
lower than that for next year
thank you
the next question is from the line of
chaitan tucker from esk investment
managers please go in good evening sir
as the two questions uh one is on the
health side
just wanted to understand how should we
view combined over a longer term
both for group and retail put together
and the mix that you're targeting
the second would be on the 775 crore
expense that is there in the shareholder
account which does not pertain to the
insurance business so what does that
exactly pertain to
those are expenses not related to the
insurance business uh that's more a
classification requirement in accordance
with the regulatory prescription
just to kind of explain this
i think the regulator has laid down
limits for all players in the market to
comply with limits on expenses of
management for the company as a whole
for isis lombard we are in compliance
with those limits for the at an
aggregate level
having said that what the regulator is
also stipulated is individual limits for
some of the top segments of businesses
within the aggregate portfolio
and in case if in any of those sub
segments if the actual
based on the allocation of expenses that
have happened to those individual sub
segments in case if we exceed
then to that exchange from a
classification standpoint those amounts
are separately required to be given
on the face of the profit and loss
statement which is why you find
a large amount being reflected there but
equally when you possibly see
the revenue account statement what is
the counter entry there which i saw here
that is moving from shareholder to
policy holder and then moving back
exactly so it's more a classification
requirement that is stipulated in so far
as regulatory guidelines are concerned
but as i said for iso lombard at an
aggregate level in accordance with the
requirement of regulation we are in
compliance with those limits of expenses
so that is helpful
and coming back to your second question
first question on on health look at this
stage uh you know gopal explained the
corporate book it is a high loss ratio
business in the 90s but the cost of
sourcing is low so
it stays in the you know just shared
above 100 100
because
uh you know
that volume also helps us in terms of
the network and all the other aspects
that corporate relationships plus we are
doing a lot of work with the iot care
app with corporates to see what we can
do in terms of cluster and upset so
that's something that we want to stay
invested but that's the kind of range
that we expect going ahead uh on the
retail we are investing and that's why
when i you know in my opening remarks i
talked about the overall investment that
we are making making and distribution
and
and technology
uh so retail indemnity the the the
health agency team that we are scaling
up obviously at this point in time is
usually highly combined ratio
our sense is that you know it will take
over a couple of years for for us to see
that coming in line with our numbers
because we want to keep on investing uh
you know in that segment for uh for some
time at least for the next couple of
years so the next five years out would
combined for health uh be a number that
we can work with so i understand it will
be a build up and then things will scale
up i just wanted a more longer term
picture
you know i always uh i'm very worried
about predicting five year out numbers
because none of us can find
five-year-old numbers
uh my sense is that of course the
combined would obviously come under much
better control
i do not believe that the number can be
a low 90s that some people articulate we
don't believe that that can sustain in
the indian markets you have to operate
at you know combined ratios which are
maybe closer to 100 not closer to 90.
okay that is helpful thank you so much
for this all the way
thank you the next question is from the
line of pradeep from nippon indian
mutual fund please go ahead
yeah sir hi for just one small uh
clarification uh did i hear you right
saying that you know you have diluted
your ro aspirations uh for growth
and hence uh the journey to that hazard
taking combined ratio might not be
something which we would look for
yes what we've been saying is that you
would want to invest in some of these
segments of business largely digital and
health agency and we had said that
while we on the integrated basis in our
performances we were about 104 odd
number if you look at a 2020 performer
we had said that we would want to bring
it down closer to our normal target
number of 100 but we do want to invest a
bit in terms of scaling up these
businesses towards that if the roi comes
down below 20 we are okay it will be in
the high teams may not be 20 percent
but is this because of competitive
pressures that or or it is just a more
strategic uh
question or order
like what has changed for you to you
know
i remember earlier in our conversations
always the focus was on rve and
you know non-diluting the combined
issues
looks like there has been some change
so bit of both honestly if you see the
on the health side it's more strategic
uh because of the investment that we if
you remember some of the conversations
that we've had that on the health in
community side we were building up some
of the capabilities
both in the outpatient opd product and
the ielts care app now that we've done
that we want to kill up the business so
that's an that's a strategic call
the rest of course driven by current
context in the market the if the market
remains very aggressive then you know we
don't want to uh you know kind of lose
market share beyond the level
if however market connects you know
there will be an opportunity being
combined down under uh into our you know
comfort zone but at this point in time
it's a big bit of both you know
investment both in your agency and also
in digital
to scale up the business for the future
thanks thank you
thank you
the next question
from is town securities please go ahead
yeah you for giving me the opportunity
since out of the 88 000 agents that we
have mentioned how many would be selling
health for us and also in continuation
with health
ict bank has started selling indemnity
how much of this can we kind of uh
like go up or what what can be the
growth path here and also is there any
update on hdfc bank and access selling
health for us or after vacation
partnership
you know the key bank of partners that
we got through the
acquisition we are very happy with the
way those partnerships are developing
as of now they are primarily focusing on
sme
and motor products
but i'm sure there will be opportunities
to distribute health in due course
and if you see the growth of of that
channel while
the aggregate bank of partners of uh
baji as we said is grown at about 15.9
i think these two partners have grown
even faster so we are quite happy with
the way that that those channels are
shaping up uh
coming to your
question on the uh bank business
look i think you know we've we've been
talking about the fact that we had a
base attack because of this decision of
the bank not to sell benefit policies
for you know from
q3 of the previous year and that had a
impact for this year number for nine
months
that and we've been saying that that uh
you know the that that base effect will
play out in this quarter what the bank
has
decided to do is rather selling benefit
they are keen to sell selling limited so
we kind of structure suitable products
for the bank and we've launched it
i don't want to give any guidance on
whether the number will go up or not or
down because
uh at this point in time we just started
selling some of these products we will
see how it goes along and then we will
we will see uh what numbers we see but
at least the base uh
the negative base that we had of the
benefit book being there the previous
year and
you know that business being stopped
this year that effect has now gone
and your last question on
the number of
health agents within that number will be
about 6000
okay
so last quarter we have added about
eight to ten thousand agents so not all
of them are obviously health um
yeah we have three separate agency
channels one is motor one is health one
is sme of course we
you know we work across the channels and
try to cost them
but we have dedicated channels for the
three segments
okay
okay let's just ask if i can squeeze it
our advanced premium number for march is
lower than december so that means moto
tp growth is more towards cv is that
understanding correct or it is towards
renewable premiums
the combination of both
i think relatively
you're right to some extent given the
fact that let's say the contribution of
cv in the overall motor growth is also
kind of uh higher in fi 22 compared to
521 so that's obviously one contributor
having said that i think equally if you
look at some of the older apps
what we had said even at the time when
these long term policy guidelines had
come in we had said it will start to
kind of peak
maybe after attaining almost about three
to between the third and the fourth
years this number of advanced premium
will pretty much start to kind of peak
uh because you will obviously start to
have
the incremental numbers or advanced
premium will be more reflective of what
kind of growth that we have that we will
achieve on the motor portfolio which is
what we have seen
in f5 20 21 22 this is the year where
it's been almost about three years since
the time the new
long-term guidelines had come so hence
that's the reason why you see a small
dip in so far as the advanced primary
numbers are 30 first matches that's uh
you know the other thing that we've been
saying that new vehicle sales both for
private car and two wheelers have been
quite low that has also happened
sir
thank you
next question is from the lineup from
investigate please go ahead
uh thanks for the opportunity two
questions but firstly a lot of
inshore tech companies are scaling their
boss
agency business
uh so how do we view this business do we
see it as a threat or opportunity for us
uh secondly uh in the new vehicle new
private cars segment have we have been
lost my mark how the market share trends
in that segment have we lost market
share gained market share in last one
year and just in the new private sector
private car technology
so this is
again second question first in the nine
months we lost market share uh that's
why our you know if you see our motor
numbers were
quite low in the you know relatively
lower in the first nine months
this uh you know this quarter we have
not lost as much we've lost a little bit
in the private car side but made up in
the two-wheeler and the cv side
on the quarter and our sense is that
even on private car the recalibration on
the portfolio alignment that we wanted
to do given the pricing aggression with
largely largely behind us so we should
we hope to see
the market share even in private car
segment being held on
uh coming back to the first question on
insure tech look uh in
you know at this point in time we are
partnering with almost all of them
uh in terms of whether in the long term
it's uh it's positive or negative you
know there's one positive in terms of
them potentially expanding as of now
they're not expanding the market really
because they're
more playing like aggregators
aggregating existing agents under their
uh their
umbrella but we hope that in due course
they will expand the market and grow and
we are
at this point in time we are working
with all of them uh
on the post side we are not with the
digital aggregator but on this segment
we are working with them
sure okay thank you sir
thank you
the next question is from the line of
nation
from kodak securities please go ahead
oh hi am i audible
definition
yeah
uh my question actually pertains to the
last two slides of the present
and uh i think what you mentioned is
that based on the revised disclosures uh
you have split the reserving of you know
triangle disclosure between motor tp and
the others
now i think what we can see over here is
that the releasing in the other segment
is higher than motor tp uh if i look at
it you know i mean over the years so how
should one really be reading it what is
the interpretation of it is it something
that uh we're
describing in the other segments or i
mean
if you could just help us interpret this
so distance if you look at uh so far as
approach to reserving is concerned
fundamentally there is no change
uh in terms of the process that we
follow uh for the current year relative
to let's say what approach we have been
following over the last several years
and the approach is to kind of reserve
conservatively at source
and as and when each portfolio kind of
starts to develop in terms of loss
experiences
you will possibly see whether the
reserve estimates that we made it source
was adequate or not so adequate in some
of these lines the conservativeism of
reserving will start to play out faster
however in certain long tail lines of
businesses that will obviously take a
relatively longer time for you to
reflect
whether the reserves that we carried at
source were adequate or not
uh flight 29 and 30 the point that you
made other than motor third party lines
of businesses are predominantly
which have a relatively shorter tail in
so far as claim settlements is concerned
which is why
the play out of the actual loss
experience tends to be faster and you
are able to kind of see relative to the
amount of reserves that we carry
you are able to see let's say small
amount of reserve releases however
in so far as the third party book is
concerned as i said that's a book which
is long tail
and obviously it takes a longer horizon
before which one can say whether the
amount of reserves that we have kind of
built in is appropriate or not having
said that if you look at the information
that gets put out whether it is for
motor third party or whether it is for
the other other lines of distances other
than third party
the information is given for the last 10
years
and you can see over the last 10-year
cycles
even after 10 years of
development
both with respect to the motor third
party triangles that you see as well as
the other than motor third party
triangles
this is the loss development experiences
our approach to reserving has paid out
to be conservative at source
and both of them reflect small amount of
reserve releases in the portfolio
and if i can add to what gopal said we
are actually very happy that this
managed by the regulator we've been
asking for this disclosure for a long
long time
we were the first company to disclose
and now we are seeing more disclosures
it's not just the two
uh you know pool and aggregate there's
further disclosures of you know tp
business for the running book and the
non-degree business which is a very good
development
thank you very much
ladies and gentlemen we'll take that as
a last question
i now hand the conference mr vargas
gupta for closing comments
thank you thank you everyone for joining
and again you know if you have any other
separate questions feel free to reach
out we'll be happy to take them
separately thank you again thank you so
much take care and good night
thank you very much
on behalf of icici lombard general
insurance company limited that concludes
this conference thank you for joining us
you may now disconnect your lines
thank you